-------------------------------------------------
Typical example for main input file version 5
-------------------------------------------------

<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "UTF-8" standalone = "yes"?>
<computationParam>
  <run>example</run>
  <outputMode format="XML" binary="false" precision="10"/>
  <timeControlMode iterations="false">
    <iterations number="3" iterFreq="1"/>
    <physicalTime totalTime="8.e-3" timeFreq="8.e-4"/>
  </timeControlMode>
  <computationControl CFL="0.8"/>
</computationParam>

----------------------------------
REQUIRED computational parameters
----------------------------------

1) Run name
***********
The run name correspond to the created folder name with results (in folder ECOGEN/results/)
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<run>example</run>    
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

2) Output mode
**************
Allow choice for output format
Implemented format: XML ou GNU
Binary mode: false (ASCII) or true (binary)
Options: precision of output files (number of digits). If not precised, set as default.
         reduced number of output variables when possible (depends on the model). Only available for velocity and pressure-velocity equilibrium model. If not precised, default is false (complete output).
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<outputMode format="XML" binary="false" precision="10" reducedOutput="true"/>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

3) Time control mode
********************
Choice for simuation time control, two possibilities:
a) iterations="true": control the simulation time using iteration number. Output printing frequency is set in iteration number.
b) iterations="false": control the simulation time using a physical time in seconds. Output frequency printing is set in physical time in seconds
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<timeControlMode iterations="false">
  <iterations number="3" iterFreq="1"/>
  <physicalTime totalTime="8.e-3" timeFreq="8.e-4"/>
</timeControlMode>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

4) CFL criteria (Courant number ratio)
**************************************
Set a security marge accordingly to numerical scheme stability (real lower than 1.)
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<computationControl CFL="0.8"/>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

----------------------------------
OPTIONNAL computationnal parameters
----------------------------------

*) Scheme precision order
*************************
Default (without this XML node), the scheme is first order in time and space. Possible using of a second-order scheme in time and space using MUSCL method with TVD limiters (currently only available for Cartesian mesh with/without AMR).
Available limiters are: minmod, vanleer, vanalbada, mc, superbee, thinc (only for volume-fraction limiter).
The choice of the limiters is divided into four parts:
- global limiter: applied everywhere and on all variables unless it is overwrite by the following optional limiters.
- interface limiter: applied on all variables but only at the interface location. By default is equal to the global limiter.
- global volume-fraction limiter: applied everywhere but only on the volume-fraction and transport equations (THINC is only applied on the volume fractions) unless it is overwrite by the interface volume-fraction limiter. By default is equal to the global limiter.
- interface volume-fraction limiter: applied only at the interface location and on the volume-fraction and transport equations (THINC is only applied on the volume fractions). By default is equal to the interface limiter.
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<secondOrder>
  <globalLimiter>minmod</globalLimiter>
  <interfaceLimiter>superbee</interfaceLimiter>                            <!-- optionnal node -->
  <globalVolumeFractionLimiter>minmod</globalVolumeFractionLimiter>        <!-- optionnal node -->
  <interfaceVolumeFractionLimiter>thinc</interfaceVolumeFractionLimiter>   <!-- optionnal node -->
</secondOrder>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

*) Gradient method
******************
To compute gradients, e.g. density gradient or viscous gradient, it is possible to use finite-difference-like gradient on Cartesian mesh (also with AMR) or Green-Gauss gradient on Cartesian and unstructured mesh.
Default (without this XML node), the gradients will be computed using the finite-difference scheme (<method>finite-difference</method>).
To define explicitly the gradient method or use the Green-Gauss one (<method>green-gauss</method>), one can use:
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<gradient>
  <method>finite-difference</method> <!-- For finite difference like gradient scheme -->
</gradient>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

*) Restart a simulation
***********************
Restart a finished computation from the result file number. For AMR simulations, one also needs to specify the frequency at which restarts are saved (default is 0).
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<restartSimulation restartFileNumber="15" AMRsaveFreq="5"/>                <!-- optionnal node -->
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

*) Record specific information
******************************
Some specific recording methods are available below. 
Note that all these methods can use a given precision (number of digits). 
The precision parameter must be added to the method such as:
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<boundary record="flux" precision="10">
 ...
</boundary>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

a) 1D output Cut
----------------
Possibility to extract 1D output cuts from multiD computations. Define a line using a vertex and direction vector.
Cut results will be placed in the corresponding results folder under GNU format.
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<cut1D>
  <vertex x="0" y="0.0001" z="0.5"/>
  <vecDir x="1" y="1" z="0"/>
</cut1D>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

b) 2D output cut
----------------
Possibility to extract 2D output cuts from 3D computations. Define a plane using a vertex and normal vector.
Cut results will be placed in the corresponding results folder under GNU format.
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<cut2D>
  <vertex x="0.51" y="0.51" z="0.51"/>
  <vecNormal x="1" y="0" z="0"/>
</cut2D>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

c) Probes
---------
Adding probes at chosen location in the physical domain. Define a name, a vertex and time recording parameters
<probe name="sensor1">
  <vertex x="0.51" y="0.51" z="0.51"/>
  <timeControl acqFreq="-1."/>       <!-- if negative or nul, recording at each time step -->
</probe>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

d) Boundaries
-------------
It is possible to extract data on a given boundary. It could be either a flux type (record="flux") or all quantities (record="all") following density, velocity, pressure and surface.
This feature is only available on Cartesian grids without AMR and on unstructured meshes.
It is mandatory to define the name, boundary number and time recording parameters.
To record several information on the same boundary, it is necessary to set the boundary node for each information.
Boundary results will be placed into the corresponding results folder under GNU format.
Flux recording is done with the flux node and it allows to extract massflow (type="massflow") or power flux (type="powerflux").
No specific node is required to extract all quantities.
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<boundary record="flux">
  <boundaryID number="1" name="massflow-inflow"/>
  <timeControl acqFreq="-1."/>       <!-- if negative or nul, recording at each time step -->
  <flux type="massflow"/>
</boundary>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines

e) Global quantity
------------------
Possibility to record a global quantity on whole domain. Could be mass or total energy.
Global quantity results will be placed in the corresponding results folder under GNU format.
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines
<globalQuantity quantity="mass"/>
%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%%% << copy between these lines